Society for the Preservation of Water Resources; Records apap061
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Society for the Preservation of Water Resources Records
1918-1999
1981-1999
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Society for the Preservation of Water Resources
apap061
12.46 cubic ft. (excludes map portion of collection)
Documents major projects the society undertook to protect water resources, including the Wilmorite project, the Bonded Concrete project, and the water supply applications of the city of Schenectady and the town of Rotterdam.
Administrative History
The Society for the Preservation of Water Resources, Inc. (SPWR), was incorporated on June 24, 1981 as the Society for the Preservation of the Aquifer, a not-for-profit corporation "to promote the protection of Schenectady County water resources; to encourage citizen participation in the decision making process affecting water resources; to educate the community on issues having direct or implied consequences for county water resources; to spearhead activities designed to protect the County's water resources from compromise; and to raise funds". The members of the association were mostly engineers and scientists, people with the technical background to understand the problems they were addressing.
The administrative structure of the association was simple: a president, a vice-president and a secretary/treasurer. The members met periodically to discuss their concerns and to plan their strategy. They encouraged the public to take an interest in preserving their water resources and they worked together with others to try to reach their goals.
As preserving the purity of the Great Flats Aquifer of Schenectady County was their major concern, the Society for the Preservation of the Aquifer was also known as SPA, an acronym that people could remember. One of the organization's major projects was to prevent Wilmorite, Inc., from building Rotterdam Square Mall (which at one point was being called Westview Mall) over the aquifer. The society came up with alternate sites for the mall, including the site for Broadway Mall, a mall proposed but never built for downtown Schenectady. The group was interested in other possible threats to the aquifer, including the town of Rotterdam's proposed outfall sewer line over the aquifer and the leaking of gas from a Mobil gas station near a critical area of the aquifer. The group also followed the course of the water supply applications that the city of Schenectady and the town of Rotterdam submitted to the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation. The water supply applications were apparent attempts to gain control over and, therefore, protect critical areas of the aquifer. SPWR also worked to keep Bonded Concrete from mining gravel from the aquifer and tried to stop other projects such as the Guildercrest development and the Schermerhorn Hollow Village complex that interfered with the Schenectady County aquifer [Kagay, John, telephone conversation, 24 October 1988].
Scope and Contents
The bulk of the records of the Society for the Preservation of Water Resources consist of files on the major projects the society undertook, such as the Wilmorite project, the Bonded Concrete project, and the water supply applications of the city of Schenectady and the town of Rotterdam (1982-1985). As most of these projects concerned legal questions, the files consist primarily of legal papers not produced by SPWR, but many include notes by SPWR. The records for each of these projects form a complete record of the legal proceedings for each project including testimony by expert witnesses for SPWR. However, little information about the SPWR's strategies can be gleaned from this material. For instance, the records provide little evidence that the society was interested in the Broadway Mall project (1960, 1980-1981) because they thought the site for the Broadway Mall might be a possible alternate site for Wilmorite's Rotterdam Square Mall.
The news clippings (1978-1992) appear to be complete and these contain some general clippings on water problems as well as much information about the history of the projects that the society worked on, but not necessarily from the point of view of SPWR. These clippings do have some information on entire projects that are not easy to find elsewhere in the records. One instance of this might be the SPWR project that concerned gasoline leaking from a service station over the aquifer. This was a very small project that required no legal moves, and therefore there is no separate series on this project. The news clippings series is probably the best place to find this information. Even the meeting minutes (1981-1987) and the day file (1981-1985) would be little help, because these generally contain little more than sketchy notes and most of them are difficult to read because they are handwritten.
The large maps and photographs (1975, 1978-1981) are often useful to help a researcher visualize where the controversies took place. There is little material in the general files (1981-1985, 1988, 1991), but it does give a broad idea of the goals and the strategies of the Society for the Preservation of Water Resources. Overall, these records greatly favor information from the Wilmorite Project, which makes up nearly half of the available content.
This collection was donated to the University Libraries in two separate accessions 17 years apart. The first donation consisted of 7 cubic feet of material, while the second donation was over 5 cubic feet of material. Because the first donation of material had already been processed before the arrival of the remaining material, consideration had to be made on how to combine the records. The newer accessioned material was for the most part added to the ends of existing series, so researchers will note that there are separate alphabetic arrangements within series 4, 6, and 8. The records processed in 1988 were not altered, which also explains why series 4, 6, and 8 are not housed in sequentially numbered boxes.
Arrangement of the Collection
Divided into 10 topical series.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by John Kagay of the Society for the Preservation of Water Resources on March 2, 1988. An additional accession was received in July 2005 from Marjorie Kagay.
Related Materials
Related Collections in the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives can be found in the subject guide for Conservation and the Environment. Of particular interest are the papers of Vincent J. Schaefer (UA-902.010), who was also opposed to the construction of Rotterdam Square Mall.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Citizens’ associations -- New York (State) -- Rotterdam.; City planning -- New York (State) -- Rotterdam.; Zoning law -- New York (State) -- Rotterdam.; Environmental protection -- New York (State) -- Citizen participation.; Shopping malls -- New York (State).; Water resources development -- New York (State) -- Citizen participation.; Great Flats Aquifer (N.Y.); Minutes.; Maps.; Photographs.; Drawing.; Clippings (information artifacts).; Agenda.; Agriculture; Conservation and the Environment; Neighborhood and Community Associations; Schenectady, New York; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Wilmorite, Inc.; Bonded Concrete, Inc.; Rotterdam Square Mall.
- General Files, 1981-1991; 1; 0.1 cubic ft.
  Scope and Contents
  The series include by-laws, issues files, drafts for a brochure, and other files that deal with the general administration of the Society for the Preservation of Water Resources.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Background Information File, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 1)
  - By-laws, 1981-1985 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 2)
  - Coalition to Protect the Aquifer, Committees, 1982 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 4)
  - Education Program, Plan of Action, ca. 1982 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 5)
  - Issues, Statements on, 1980-1982 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 6)
  - Press Releases, 1981-1982 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 7)
  - Society for the Preservation of the Aquifer, Brochure, Drafts, ca. 1982 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 8)
  - Acid Rain Information, 1988 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 8a)
  - Annual Reports, 1981; 1983-1985; 1999 (Box 1 (1-General Files), Folder 8b)
- Day Files, 1981-1985; 2; 0.9 cubic ft.
  A day by day accounting of the work of the SPWR including outgoing and incoming correspondence, notes, entries about telephone calls, and meeting agenda. Also includes, at the beginning of each new chronological group, an enumeration of each item. The size of each chronological group depends on the number of sheets that fit into the ring binder in which each group was originally filed.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Day Files, 1981 March-1981 August (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 9)
  - Day Files, 1981 August-1982 March (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 10)
  - Day Files, 1982 April-1982 August (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 11)
  - Day Files, 1982 August-1982 November (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 12)
  - Day Files, 1982 November (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 13)
  - Day Files, 1982 December-1983 February (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 14)
  - Day Files, 1983 March (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 15)
  - Day Files, 1983 April-1983 July (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 16)
  - Day Files, 1983 July (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 17)
  - Day Files, 1983 August (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 18-19)
  - Day Files, 1983 September-1983 October (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 20)
  - Day Files, 1983 October-1983 December (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 21)
  - Day Files, 1984 January-1984 March (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 22)
  - Day Files, 1984 March-1984 June (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 24)
  - Day Files, 1984 June-1984 July (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 25)
  - Day Files, 1984 September-1984 November (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 26)
  - Day Files, 1984 November-1985 March (Box 1 (2-Day Files), Folder 27)
- Meeting Minutes and Agenda, 1981-1987; 3; 0.1 cubic ft.
  This series includes meeting minutes and agenda, including meeting notices, sign-in sheets for meetings, and notes.
  - Agenda, 1981 May-1981 August (Box 2 (3-Meeting Minutes and Agenda), Folder 1)
  - Minutes and Agenda, 1981 May-1983 June (Box 2 (3-Meeting Minutes and Agenda), Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1983 June-1987 March (Box 2 (3-Meeting Minutes and Agenda), Folder 3)
- Wilmorite Project, 1918-1995; 4; 5.43 cubic ft.
  Records concerning the Society for the Preservation of Water Resources' project to keep Wilmorite, Inc., from building Rotterdam Square Mall over the Great Falls Aquifer. Includes hearing transcripts, intervention papers, petitions, environmental and other studies, draft environmental impact statements (DEIS), briefs, reply briefs, statements of concern, and other papers dealing with this project. A related series is the "Broadway Mall Project" which interested SPWR because the site for that proposed mall might have been an alternate site for Wilmorite's mall. Also related to this series is the water supply applications, which contains records of attempts by the city of Schenectady and the town of Rotterdam to buy land over the aquifer in order to protect their water supply.
  The material in this series was acquired in two separate accessions several years apart and the arrangement of the series reflects this. The records accessioned in 1988 can be found in boxes 2-4 and are in alphabetical order. The records accessioned in 2005 can be found in boxes 7-10. This material is arranged by topic, with most of the individual topics being arranged in alphabetical order. Boxes 7A and 9A contain folders with legal size material.
  - Aquifer, Reports, Correspondence, News Clippings, 1978; 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Aquifer Preservation Study and Report by Schenectady County, 1978 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 5-6)
  - Briefs from City and County of Schenectady and the Society for the Preservation of the Aquifer, 1982 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 7)
  - Briefs from City of Schenectady and Wilmorite, 1983 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 8)
  - Conservation Publications, Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 10-11)
  - Correspondence from Schenectady County Board of Directors, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 12)
  - Cultural Resources Affected by Rotterdam Square Mall, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 13)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement, 1981 April (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 14)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement, Notes and Allied Material, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 15)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement, Response to Comments on, 17 December 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 16)
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement, Responses, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 17)
  - Flood Assessment, Report and Correspondence, 1977; 1979; 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 18)
  - Flood Storage Calculations by John Kagay, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 19-21)
  - Flooding and Drainage Problems, Reports and Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 22)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Transcripts, ca. 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 23)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Transcript, 11 December 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 24)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Notes by John Kagay, 1982 January-1982 February (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 25-26)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Transcript, 4 January 1983 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 27)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Transcript, 21 January 1983 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 28)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Transcript, 26 January 1983 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 29)
  - Hearings, Department of Environmental Conservation, Transcript, 27 January 1983 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 30)
  - Hearings, Environmental Protection Agency, Statement for, 1983 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 31)
  - Hearings, Intervention by City of Schenectady, 1981 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 32)
  - Hearings, Intervention by City of Schenectady, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 33)
  - Hearings, Intervention by County of Schenectady, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Department of Environmental Conservation, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 2)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Department of Environmental Conservation, 1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 3)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Department of Health, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Schmid, Marjorie L., 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 5)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Sierra Club, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 6)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Society for the Preservation of the Aquifer, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 7)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Society for the Preservation of the Aquifer, 1981-1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 8)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Town of Niskayuna, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 9)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Town of Niskayuna, 1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 10)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Town of Rotterday, 1981-1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 11)
  - Hearings, Intervention by Wilmorite, 1981-1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 12-13)
  - Hearings, Notes and Correspondence, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 14)
  - Hearings, Witnesses, Expert, for SPA, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 15)
  - Hydrologic and Hydraulic Analysis of Alternate "C" for Rotterdam Square, 1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 16)
  - Interim Decision of the Commissioner, 7 October 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 17)
  - Maps Granting a Zoning Change, and Notes of Marjorie Schmid, 1985 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 18)
  - Party Consolidation Summary, 9 September 1981 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 19)
  - Petitions Against Rotterdam Square Mall, 1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 20)
  - Petitions Against Rotterdam Square Mall, 1984 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 21)
  - Petitions Against Rotterdam Square Mall, ca. 1984 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 22-24)
  - Petitions Against Rotterdam Square Mall, to Rotterdam Town Board, 1983 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 25)
  - Petitions Against Rotterdam Square Mall, with Notes, 1981-1983 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 26)
  - Petitions Against Rotterdam Square Mall, 1983 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 27-28)
  - Poentic Kill, Stream Channel Shading, 1985 July (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 29-31)
  - Pre-Adjudicatory Hearing Conference for Proposed Rotterdam Square Mall, 1981 September (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 32)
  - Real Estate Value Study of Rotterdam Mall Site Value, 1985 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 33)
  - Reply Briefs from City and County of Schenectady, Wilmorite, and Department of Environmental Conservation, 1982 (Box 3 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 34)
  - Requests for Party Status by Various Groups, 1981 August-1981 September (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)
  - Resumes of Witnesses, 1981 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 2)
  - Rulings on Proposed Rotterdam Square Mall, and Reactions, 1981-1983 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 3)
  - Statements of Concern, Decisions and Responses to, by SPA, 1982 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Statements of Concern, Impact on Transportation, 1981 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 5)
  - Statements of Concern, Industry, General Electric, 1981 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 6)
  - Traffic, Rotterdam Square, Reports and Correspondence, 1977 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 7)
  - Vedder Family Cemetery, 1981-1983 (Box 4 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 8)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1981 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1982 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 2-3)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1983 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1984 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 5)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1985 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 6)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1986 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 7-8)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1987 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 9)
  - Wilmorite Information, 1988 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 10)
  - Wilmorite and Sear-Brown Information, 1982; 1984 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 11)
  - Wilmorite and Sear-Brown Information, 1984; 1986; 1988 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 12)
  - Wilmorite, Ground Water Information, 1984-1989 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 13)
  - Wilmorite, Schenectady Water Supply, 1989 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 14)
  - Wilmorite, Test Boring Logs and Jar Sample Classifications, 1977; 1980 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 15)
  - Wilmorite, Water Initiative and Soil Conservation Service, 1989; 1993 (Box 7 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 16)
  - Wilmorite Information, ca. 1981 (Box 7A (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)
  - Wilmorite Information, Undated (Box 7A (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 2)
  - Wilmorite and Sear-Brown Information, 1981-1982 (Box 7A (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 3)
  - Wilmorite, Schenectady Water Supply, 1937; 1952; 1965; 1983-1985 (Box 7A (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Applications and Responses, 1981-1984; 1986; Undated (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Applications and Responses, 1993 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 2)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Briefs, 1982 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 3)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Briefs, 1982; 1985 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Briefs, Undated (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 5)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Comments, Responses, and Statements, 1977; 1982; 1984; Undated (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 6)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Hearings, 1981; 1983-1985; 1987 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 7)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Memorandums, 1981-1982; 1984-1985 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 8)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Mitigation Plan, 1981 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 9)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Permits, 1982-1985 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 10)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Petitions, 1983 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 11)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Responses to Comments, 1981 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 12)
  - Wilmorite, Court Documents, Testimonies, 1981-1982; 1985; Undated (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 13)
  - Wilmorite, Environmental Publications and Reports, 1976; 1985; 1988; 1990-1991 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 14)
  - Wilmorite, Environmental Publications and Reports, 1985-1986; 1988-1989 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 15)
  - Wilmorite, Environmental Publications and Reports, 1994-1995 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 16)
  - Wilmorite, News Flyers, 1981; 1984; 1988-1991; Undated (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 17)
  - Wilmorite, Real Estate Value Study, 1985 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 18)
  - Wilmorite, Rotterdam Town Park and Aquifer Information, 1993; 1995 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 19)
  - Wilmorite, Traffic Reports, 1984 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 20)
  - Wilmorite, Schmid, Marjorie, 1988 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 21)
  - Wilmorite, Maps, 1981; 1984 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 22)
  - Wilmorite, Schenectady Aquifer, Poentic Kill Fish Problems, 1980-1983 (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 23)
  - Wilmorite, Schenectady Aquifer, Poentic Kill Fish Problems, 1984-1985; 1988-1989; 1991; 1995; Undated (Box 8 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 24)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, "A Visit to the Vedder Cemetery", and Other News, 1982 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Surveys and Archeology Reports, Comments on, 1982 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 2)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Vedder Cemetery, Forms, 1982 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 3)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, DeForest, Henry Schermerhorn, 1917-1918 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 4)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Vedder Family, Letters and Responses, 1982 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 5)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Schenectady History and Cemetery Information, News Clippings, 1985 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 6)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Vedder Family Information, Miscellaneous, 1982-1984 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 7)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Vedder Family Information, Miscellaneous, 1983-1984 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 8)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Wilmorite and the Vedder Cemetery, 1983; 1985; Undated (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 9)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Wilmorite and the Vedder Cemetery: Wright, Henry D., 1982-1983; 1985 (Box 9 (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 10)
  - Wilmorite, Historic Land Preservation, Wilmorite and the Vedder Cemetery, Pre-1980, 1982 (Box 9A (4-Wilmorite Project), Folder 1)